axainsurance.com 2014-05-10

# Privacy Policy | AXA Insurance

AXA > Privacy 

  * How we use your information and who we share it with
  * Using your online account
  * Fraud prevention agencies
  * Protecting your personal information
  * Use of your personal information
  * Collection of information
  * Exchange of information
  * Preventing and detecting fraud
  * Motor Insurance Database
  * Additional products
  * Credit reference agencies
  * Use of personal information for marketing
  * Dealing with other people
  * Automatic renewals
  * Sensitive personal information
  * Cookies
  * Further information

Your privacy is important to us and we promise we will respect your personal information. We will use your information to manage your insurance with us, including underwriting, claims handling, No Claims Discount entitlement and statistical analysis. This may include disclosing your information within the AXA Group and to agents, suppliers, other insurers, or reinsurers who provide services on our behalf. 

We do not disclose your information to anyone outside the AXA Group except: 

  * Where we have your permission; or
  * Where we are required or permitted to do so by law; or
  * To other companies who provide a service to us or you which includes proof of No Claims Discount (NCD) entitlement; or
  * Where we may transfer rights and obligations under this agreement.

We may transfer your information to other countries including those located outside the European Economic Area. If we do this we will seek to ensure that anyone to whom we pass it provides an adequate level of protection. 

Back to top

## Using your online account

When you set up your first policy with AXA, you need to set up an online account (My AXA Account). In My AXA Account, you can:

  * View and print all your policy information and documents
  * Securely make changes to your policy yourself whenever you want

To set up and use My AXA Account, you'll need:

  * Your email address, which you give us when you buy your policy 
  * A memorable password which you can choose
  * To answer an additional security question when you first set up your account

By using the same email address when buying additional AXA policies, your new documents will be stored to your existing online account. You can then view all your details in the same AXA Account. If you prefer your new policy to be saved in a different online account, you will need to use a different email address. 

We recommend that you do not share your account details with anyone. If you do give your email address and password to another person, they will have all your privileges, and will be able to view or change your cover or details. In these instances you will be responsible for their actions, and AXA cannot accept any responsibility for any adjustment made without your authority. 

Because circumstances can change, you should review your access details regularly to make sure they are still appropriate for you and anyone you have given permission to access your account. 

To set up a separate account for one or more of your existing policies, please contact our help team.

If we’re contacted by phone we won’t discuss the policy with anybody other than the policyholder unless we already have their explicit consent. See  Dealing with other people below.

Back to top

## Fraud prevention agencies

To keep premiums low we participate in a number of industry initiatives to prevent and detect fraud. To help prevent crime we may at any time: 

  * Approach the DVLA to check all or any relevant driving licence details of anyone named on the policy; 
  * Share information about you with other organisations and public bodies including the police;
  * Share information about you and any other named drivers on the policy within the AXA Group and with other insurers;
  * Pass the details you have supplied to recognised centralised insurance industry applications, policy and claims checking systems (for example the Motor Insurance Anti-Fraud and Theft Register, CUE, CIFAS and all DVLA databases) where those details will be checked and updated;
  * Check the details you have supplied with fraud prevention agencies and databases including publicly available data (for example on County Court Judgements, bankruptcy information and electoral role data). If false or inaccurate information is provided and fraud is identified, details will be passed to fraud prevention agencies to prevent fraud and money laundering;
  * Periodically search records held by fraud prevention and credit reference agencies to: 
    * help make decisions about credit services for you and your financial associates
    * help make decisions on insurance policies and claims for you and your financial associates;
    * trace debtors, recover debt, prevent fraud and to manage your insurance policies
    * check your identity to prevent money laundering.

For more information about the agencies with which we share your data, including further details explaining how the information held by fraud prevention agencies may be used, please email us at [informationsharing@axa.com](mailto:informationsharing@axa.com). 

If you would like a copy of the information we hold about you, please refer to the Further information section below. 

Back to top

## Protecting your personal information

The copyright and other intellectual property rights in this site are owned by AXA Insurance UK plc or by a third party that has given us permission to use them. 

Back to top

## Use of your personal information

Your "personal information" means any information that you have given to us, or third parties, in connection with a service or product offered whether through use of this website, by phone or in writing. 

We take your privacy very seriously and are committed to protecting your personal information. 

When you buy a product or service from us you will have access to a policy document relating to that product or service. If there is any conflict between the terms of this privacy statement and those of the specific privacy statement that applies to a particular product, then the terms of the latter will prevail. 

This document should be shown to anyone else who is covered by, or a party to, any services or policies you buy from us. We may make changes to this privacy statement from time to time. Such changes will be effective from the time they appear on the site. Therefore, you should remember to check this privacy statement from time to time. 

Back to top

## Collection of information

We collect information strictly in accordance with the Data Protection Act. When we collect personal information directly from you, if you ask for a quote or purchase a product or service from us we will do our best to ensure that information is kept up to date and accurate. Please assist us in this by advising us of any changes as soon as possible. 

We are constantly striving to improve the quality of our service and the efficiency of our systems and so, from time to time, we may use your personal information during staff training and/or system testing. 

Back to top

## Exchange of information

At various times we will exchange personal information with certain other approved organisations for underwriting and fraud prevention purposes and we may provide such information to others where required or permitted by law. Also, your personal information will sometimes be used and analysed by us and other companies in the AXA Group for the following purposes: 

  * Managing and administering products and services that we supply - in the case of insurance products this will include underwriting, reinsurance and claims handling purposes and may include disclosing your information to other insurers, reinsurers, regulatory authorities or to our agents who provide services on our behalf;
  * Considering any applications for products you may make and to help in making credit-related decisions about you where appropriate;
  * Servicing other relationships you may have within the AXA Group
  * Financial risk assessment, money laundering checks, compliance and regulatory reporting and fraud prevention;
  * Assisting in making decisions on insurance proposals, other products and any claims made by you, members of your household, and others connected with your insurance proposals and claims; and
  * Helping us and the AXA Group to develop new and innovative products and services.

We may send data in confidence for processing to other companies within the AXA Group (or companies acting on their instructions) including those operating outside the European Economic Area. By entering your details onto our website you are consenting to such use of your personal data. 

Disclosure of your information to a third party outside of the AXA Group will only be made where the third party has agreed to keep your personal information strictly confidential and use it only for the specific purpose for which we provide it to them and: 

  * It is necessary for the performance of an agreement we have with you;
  * You have given your consent to the disclosure;
  * Such disclosure is required or permitted by law;
  * We are entitled to transfer rights and/or obligations as provided under the terms of any policy you may purchase;
  * Any such third party provides benefits or services to you under or in connection with our agreement with you; or
  * It is a credit reference or fraud prevention agency.

Enhancements in technology may result in changes in the way we view, record and use your personal information. If we think the changes could be to your disadvantage, we will advise you, by email and by posting a notice of amendment on the site, at least 30 days before the changes become effective. If you then continue to use a service or product for a further 60 days we will assume you have consented to the changes. 

Back to top

## Preventing and detecting fraud

We may, at any time, employ the following processes and systems to prevent and detect fraud. 

  * Share your information across the AXA Group, with other insurers and, where we are entitled to do so under the Data Protection Act, the police and other law enforcement agencies;
  * Pass the details you have supplied to recognised centralised insurance industry applications, policy and claims checking systems (for example the Motor Insurance Anti-Fraud and Theft Register, CUE, CIFAS and all DVLA databases) where those details will be checked and updated;
  * Check the details you have supplied with fraud prevention agencies and databases including publicly available data (for example on County Court Judgements, bankruptcy information and electoral role data). If false or inaccurate information is provided and fraud is identified, details will be passed to fraud prevention agencies to prevent fraud and money laundering;
  * We and other organisations may also use and search these records to: 
    * Help make decisions about credit and credit-related services for you and your financial associates
    * Help make decisions on motor, household, credit, life and other insurance proposals and claims for you and members of your household;
    * Trace people who owe money, recover debt, prevent fraud and to manage your insurance policies;
    * Check your identity to prevent money laundering, unless you give us satisfactory proof of identity; and
    * Carry out credit searches, electoral role searches and further fraud searches.

Back to top

## Motor Insurance Database

When you take out a car insurance policy, your policy details will be added to the Motor Insurance Database ("MID"), run by the Motor Insurers' Information Centre ("MIIC"). MID data may be used by the Driver and Vehicle Licensing Agency and the Driver and Vehicle Licensing Northern Ireland for the purpose of electronic vehicle licensing and by the police for the purposes of establishing whether a driver's use of a vehicle is likely to be covered by a motor insurance policy and for preventing and detecting crime. If you are involved in an accident, whether in the UK or abroad, other UK insurers, the Motor Insurers' Bureau and MIIC may search the MID to obtain relevant policy information. 

Persons pursuing a claim in respect of a road traffic accident (including citizens of other EU countries) may be entitled to access relevant information held about you on the MID. You can find out more about this from us, or from the [Motor Insurance Bureau](http://www.mib.org.uk/Home/en/default.htm). 

Back to top

## Additional products

When you take out additional products with us or make a claim, your details will be passed to the appropriate provider as shown below: 

### Car insurance

  * Breakdown cover: AXA Assistance (UK) Limited 
  * Car claims: Supply & Incident Management Solutions Ltd
  * Glass cover: Autoglass
  * Replacement car cover: Enterprise Rent A Car Ltd 

### Home insurance

  * Legal expenses cover: Arc Legal
  * Home assistance cover: Homeserve 
  * Home claims: AXA Insurance Home Claims, Morecambe 
  * Identity theft cover: Capita 

### Travel insurance

  * Legal expenses cover: Arc Legal
  * Travel claims: AXA Assistance (UK) Limited

### Business insurance

  * Professional indemnity insurance claims: Collegiate Claims

Back to top

## Credit reference agencies

We make searches about you at credit reference agencies who will supply us with information, including information from the Electoral Register and credit information. The agencies may record details of the search whether or not this application proceeds. We may use scoring methods to assess this application and to verify your identity. Searches and other information which is provided to us and/or the credit reference agencies, about you and those with whom you are linked financially may be used by us if you, or other members of your household, apply for other facilities including insurance applications and claims. This information may also be used for debt tracing and the prevention of money laundering as well as the management of your account. 

Back to top

## Use of personal information for marketing purposes

The information you supply may be used by us, other members of the AXA Group and carefully selected third parties for research purposes or to inform you of other products or services that may be of interest to you, unless you have advised us otherwise. On each occasion that we contact you for these purposes, you will always be given the option to opt out of any further communication. 

Please note that we have the ability to retain any data that you provide on this website, even if you do not complete your quote by clicking submit/next. Such contact details and data may be used to contact you to enquire why you did not complete your quote. If you have any questions about this, please contact us. 

If you have provided your contact information to us and would prefer not to receive marketing information, or to participate in research, simply contact us to let us know. 

Back to top

## Dealing with other people

If your spouse or partner contacts us on your behalf, due to data protection, we will be unable to answer their queries. However, if you require your spouse, partner or another third party to be able to discuss your policy, please contact the  help team and inform us of whom you would like to speak on your behalf. However, this will exclude them from being able to cancel the policy as we require to speak to the policyholder regarding cancellations. 

In some exceptional circumstances we may also deal with other people who contact us on your behalf. 

We will not reveal any credit or debit card numbers to anyone other than the policyholder. 

Back to top

## Automatic renewals

Most AXA insurance customers benefit from the convenience of our automatic renewal service. Around 25 days before your renewal date we’ll email you your renewal invitation, which will also be stored in your AXA Account online for you to view or amend. If the cover’s right for you for another year, you don’t need to do anything. It’s the hassle-free way of keeping great value insurance with AXA. If you do not want to renew, just call us before your policy expiry date. 

###  How does it work?

We securely retain your payment details and if you don’t contact us we will renew your policy automatically for you. 

###  Does everyone qualify for this service?

Although most customers can benefit, not all policies can be automatically renewed \- single trip travel insurance for instance. If you are unsure whether you qualify, you can contact us. 

Back to top

## Sensitive personal information

To provide you with some of our products or services, we may need to collect and process sensitive personal information (such as information about any criminal convictions or the state of your health) about you and others who are a party to the service or product. We will only use sensitive personal data for the specific purpose for which you provide it. Please ensure that you only provide us with sensitive information about other people with their express agreement. 

Back to top

## Cookies

A cookie is a piece of information stored on the hard drive of a computer by a web server to enhance and simplify a website user's experience by identifying a user if he or she has previously accessed that website. Our full Cookie policy is available here.

Back to top

## Further information

You should be aware that any telephone calls made to us may be recorded for monitoring and training purposes and to assist us in preventing and detecting fraud. Therefore, your use of this means of communication means that you accept and consent to this. 

Under the terms of the Data Protection Act (1998) you are entitled to request a copy of the personal data we hold about you. We reserve the right to charge a fee of £10 for this service. Please contact the Data Protection Officer by email at [info@axainsurance.com](mailto:info@axainsurance.com) or in writing to Data Protection, AXA Insurance, Civic Drive, Ipswich, IP1 2AN. 

Back to top
